A Guide to the Dr. James Lewis Early Collection, 1891-1938
Radford University, University Archives, McConnell Library
University Archives, McConnell Library, Radford University
Dr. James Lewis Early Collection, 1891-1938
University Archives, McConnell Library, Radford University
031
1.0 Linear feet (1 archival box).
Contains various newspaper clippings and numerous letters to Miss Melita Rorer Wilson (fiance and later wife) collected by Dr. James Lewis Early.
Early, James L., 1876-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
An appointment for research is required. The collection is open for research. No interlibrary loan.
Accruals
No accruals are expected.
Biographical Information
Dr. James Lewis Early was a son of William K. Early and Miss Mary Louisa Belo. Dr. Early's father was a Veteran Confederate Soldier and served as a Private to Colonel A. C. Dunn and General W. E. Jones for about four years before being honorable discharged from Service. William K. Early also appears to be a close relative to General Jubal Early, Robert E. Lee's "Bad Old Man." - information came from Ancestry.com and from the materials in this collection.
James Lewis Early was born about 1876 in Virginia. He Resided in Saltville, Smyth, Virginia and worked for Mathieson Alkali Works as an Assistant Surgeon. On the evening of June 30, 1910 at 8:00 PM Dr. J. L. Early and Miss Melita Rorer Wilson were married in Radford. The Couple soon moved back to Saltville where they had a home established. Mrs. Dr. James Lewis Early was the daughter of William A. Wilson and Miss Mary Miller Wilson.
James Lewis Early was not only a prominent physician in Saltville, but he was also a prominent shooter. He loved the sport and even held onto newspaper clippings that recorded how well he did. He was also a member of the Elk's Lodge and received a postcard from the Elk House in Jacksonville, Florida.
In 1922 at the annual convocation of the Grand Lodge of Virginia he was elected deputy grand master of the Free and Accepted Masons - information came from Virginia Medical Monthly, volumes 47-48 page 727.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, photographs, and printed materials (1891-1938) document the activities of Dr. James Lewis Early and his family.
Index Terms
Early, James L., 1876-; Virginia, Southwest; Saltville (Va.)--History
Contents List
- Photos of Dr. J. L. Early and other miscellaneous people, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newspaper food recipes and clothing advertisements, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dr. J. L. Early's shooting scores listed in the newspaper, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Check of 15 dollars to First National Bank, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Southwest Corner - newspaper clipping, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clipping, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Normal Review, Vol. 7, No. 9 - Stuart, VA, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence between Rev. F.B. Layman and John Preston McConnell regarding General Early and Daniel Boon - Deed, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Happenings in Saltville - newspaper clipping, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Early/Wilson Marriage - newspaper clipping, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Death of William A. Wilson - newspaper clippings, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Golden Wedding Announcement - newspaper clipping, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Death of Mrs. W. K. Early - newspaper clipping, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Postcard from Jacksonville, Florida with mention to membership to the Elks Lodge, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letter to Mrs. W. A. Wilson from Addie Bradley Puig, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Letter to Dr. Early from friend, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence between M'ledge Moffett and Miss Anderson, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Letters to Melita, August 23-December 24, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Letters to Melita, January 2-February 7, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Letters to Melita, February 8-March 28, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Letters to Melita, April 5-28, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Letters to Melita, May 4-June 23, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Letters to Melita, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)